{
    "id": "Politica_218",
    "claim": "Great excitement and excitement has generated the next premiere of the new History Channel series “Tiranos de America”. The production, which had a budget of about 5 million dollars, focuses on the leaders of America who acceded to power in a democratic way and then seek to perpetuate themselves in it in a dictatorial way. Among the characters that will appear in the new stellar series of the History stands Nayib Bukele, who in a short time has managed to consolidate himself as one of the tyrannical figures of the continent next to characters like Castro and Chávez. The new program is said to be a full-body X-ray of populist dictators in the region, which is why the President of El Salvador himself has sought to avoid the issue of the series at all costs. I'm sorry.",
    "source": "perma.cc",
    "date": "21/06/2023",
    "veracity": 0,
    "claims": [
        {
            "claim": "Great excitement and excitement has generated the next premiere of the new History Channel series “Tiranos de America”.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did perma.cc say generated the next premiere of the History Channel series \"Tiranos de America\"?",
                    "answer": "Great excitement"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "When was the first series of Tiranos de America aired?",
                    "score": 0.7721,
                    "answers": "on 21/06/2023|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What series is Tiranos de America?",
                    "score": 0.7551,
                    "answers": "the new History Channel series “ Tiranos de America ”|pobj\tTiranos|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What series is \"Tiranos de America\"?",
                    "score": 0.7524,
                    "answers": "the next premiere of the new History Channel series “ Tiranos de America ”|dobj\tof the new History Channel series “ Tiranos de America ”|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the History Channel say about the next premiere of the new History Channel series Tiranos de America?",
                    "score": 0.7487,
                    "answers": "excitement|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the History Channel series \"Tiranos de America\"?",
                    "score": 0.7019,
                    "answers": "de|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The production, which had a budget of about 5 million dollars, focuses on the leaders of America who acceded to power in a democratic way and then seek to perpetuate themselves in it in a dictatorial way.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who said that The production focuses on the leaders of America who acceded to power in a democratic way and then seek to perpetuate themselves in it in a dictatorial way?",
                    "answer": "perma.cc"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the production focus on the leaders of America who acceded to power?",
                    "score": 0.6029,
                    "answers": "in a democratic way|prep\tdemocratic|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the budget of the production in 2023?",
                    "score": 0.5428,
                    "answers": "The production , which had a budget of about 5 million dollars ,|nsubj\tthat The production , which had a budget of about 5 million dollars , focuses on the leaders of America who acceded to power in a democratic way and then seek to perpetuate themselves in it in a dictatorial way|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is perma.cc?",
                    "score": 0.3932,
                    "answers": "on 21/06/2023|prep\t,|punct\twhich|nsubj\ta|det\t,|punct\ton the leaders of America who acceded to power in a democratic way and then seek to perpetuate themselves in it in a dictatorial way|prep\tthe leaders of America who acceded to power in a democratic way and then seek to perpetuate themselves in it in a dictatorial way|pobj\tpower|pobj\ta|det\tthen seek to perpetuate themselves in it in a dictatorial way|conj\tto|aux\tto perpetuate themselves in it in a dictatorial way|xcomp\tin it|prep\tit|pobj\ta|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Among the characters that will appear in the new stellar series of the History stands Nayib Bukele, who in a short time has managed to consolidate himself as one of the tyrannical figures of the continent next to characters like Castro and Chávez.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Nayib Bukele has managed to consolidate himself as one of what type of figures of the continent?",
                    "answer": "tyrannical figures"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What series of books has Nayib Bukele been in?",
                    "score": 0.6685,
                    "answers": "the History|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who are the characters that will appear in the new stellar series of the History series?",
                    "score": 0.5908,
                    "answers": "Among the characters that will appear in the new stellar series of the History|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Castro and Chávez?",
                    "score": 0.5556,
                    "answers": "next to characters like Castro and Chávez|advmod\tto characters like Castro and Chávez|prep\tcharacters like Castro and Chávez|pobj\tlike Castro and Chávez|prep\tCastro and Chávez|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What series is the History series about?",
                    "score": 0.5506,
                    "answers": "the new stellar series of the History|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Nayib Bukele?",
                    "score": 0.5265,
                    "answers": "perma.cc said on 21/06/2023 that Among the characters that will appear in the new stellar series of the History stands Nayib Bukele , who in a short time has managed to consolidate himself as one of the tyrannical figures of the continent next to characters like Castro and Chávez|ROOT\ton 21/06/2023|prep\tthat|mark\tthe|det\tthat|nsubj\twill|aux\tthe|det\tnew|amod\tstellar|amod\tof the History|prep\tthe|det\tthat Among the characters that will appear in the new stellar series of the History stands Nayib Bukele , who in a short time has managed to consolidate himself as one of the tyrannical figures of the continent next to characters like Castro and Chávez|ccomp\tNayib|compound\tNayib Bukele , who in a short time has managed to consolidate himself as one of the tyrannical figures of the continent next to characters like Castro and Chávez|nsubj\t,|punct\twho|nsubj\tin a short time|prep\ta|det\tshort|amod\ta short time|pobj\thas|aux\twho in a short time has managed to consolidate himself as one of the tyrannical figures of the continent next to characters like Castro and Chávez|relcl\tto|aux\tto consolidate himself as one of the tyrannical figures of the continent next to characters like Castro and Chávez|xcomp\thimself|dobj\tas one of the tyrannical figures of the continent next to characters like Castro and Chávez|prep\tone of the tyrannical figures of the continent next to characters like Castro and Chávez|pobj\tof the tyrannical figures of the continent|prep\tthe|det\tthe|det\tand|cc"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The new program is said to be a full-body X-ray of populist dictators in the region, which is why the President of El Salvador himself has sought to avoid the issue of the series at all costs.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Why has the President of El Salvador sought to avoid the issue of the X-ray?",
                    "answer": "the President of El Salvador himself has sought to avoid the issue of the series at all costs"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the President of El Salvador want to do with the program?",
                    "score": 0.5468,
                    "answers": "which is why the President of El Salvador himself has sought to avoid the issue of the series at all costs|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the program of El Salvador?",
                    "score": 0.5029,
                    "answers": "that The new program is said to be a full - body X - ray of populist dictators in the region , which is why the President of El Salvador himself has sought to avoid the issue of the series at all costs|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of the X-ray program?",
                    "score": 0.4968,
                    "answers": "to be a full - body X - ray of populist dictators in the region|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the program that President El Salvador has sought to avoid?",
                    "score": 0.4886,
                    "answers": "perma.cc said on 21/06/2023 that The new program is said to be a full - body X - ray of populist dictators in the region , which is why the President of El Salvador himself has sought to avoid the issue of the series at all costs|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who were the leaders of the new program?",
                    "score": 0.4805,
                    "answers": "populist dictators in the region|pobj"
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}